Radim Jelínek

3D Game Environment Artist

INTRODUCTION

Enthusiastic and team-oriented Game Environment Artist with several years of experience and a passion for architecture in games. Specialities include modular asset creation, PBR, medieval architecture, real-time rendering, and procedural workflows. Experienced in close collaboration with small and medium-sized teams.

EXPERIENCE

Assetbomb, Remote – 3D Material and Shader Artist

2024 - Present | Fulltime

Created textures, shaders, and assets for environments.

Utilized procedural workflows for asset creation.

Developed a Material Layering System (MLS), allowing easy adjustments to assets by the customer.

Collaborated with other artists, helped define workflows, and contributed to the Art Bible.

Volcanoids s.r.o, Czechia – 3D Game Artist

2019 - 2024 | Freelance

Produced over 50 various models, from small props to equipable items and hero models. Additionally, prototyped environment kits and shaders.

Collaborated with other artists and designers on delivering visually coherent and interesting assets.

Iterated on assets throughout the stages, and requested and applied feedback.

Documented progress with Jira, Clickup and Notion.

EDUCATION

Breda University of Applied Sciences, Breda, NL – Exchange

2022 - 2023

Cologne Game Lab, Cologne, DE – *Game Arts Bachelor*

2020 - 2024

Stockholm, Sweden

jobs@jelrad.com www.artstation.com/jelrad www.jelrad.com

SOFTWARE

Blender

Rizom UV

Substance Painter

Substance Designer

Zbrush

Marvelous Designer

Speed Tree

Affinity Designer

Photoshop

Unreal Engine

Unity

OTHER

Best Board Game Winner

Game & Mod Jam "Auswärtig gespielt" 2023

3 Games on Steam

<u>1 EA</u>, <u>1 Full Release</u>, and <u>1 Workshop Board Game</u>

Bafta Student Game Awards

Steam Game Longlisted

LANGUAGES

Czech (Native)
English (Business fluent)
German (Pre-Intermediate)